All-New Feature-Length Quest
Futurama: Bender's Game is a animation, comedy, science
fiction film directed by Dwayne Carey-Hill.
When Leela is insulted by a group of space-rednecks (like regular rednecks, but in
space), she enters the Planet Express ship in a demolition derby.
Leela emerges victorious, but when she brings the damaged ship home, and the Professor sees the
fuel gauge, he's enraged by the hit he's going to take at the Dark Matter pump.
Now the crew have to find a way to break Mom's stranglehold on starship fuel, even if they
have to wade through a Lord of the Rings-inspired fantasy-land to do it!
Philip J. Fry / Frydo / Prof. Farnsworth (voice), played by Billy West.
Turanga Leela (voice), played by Katey Sagal.
Bender (voice), played by John DiMaggio.
Mom (voice), played by Tress MacNeille.
Walt (voice), played by Maurice LaMarche.
Hermes Conrad (voice), played by Phil LaMarr.
Futurama: Bender's Game is a 2008 American direct-to-video adult animated science fantasy comedy
film and the third of the four Futurama films that make up the show's fifth season.
It was released on DVD and Blu-ray on November 4, 2008.
According to the Beast with a Billion Backs DVD commentary, the film, which spoofs Dungeons &
Dragons, was in production when Dungeons & Dragons creator, Gary Gygax, died.
The film contains a post-credits tribute to Gygax in the form of a title card
and a clip of him from the episode "Anthology of Interest I".
Elements of J.
Tolkien's The Lord of the Rings and George Lucas' Star Wars are also parodied.
The title of the film is a pun on the book Ender's Game, by Orson Scott Card, though the
Futurama film has "very little to do with the subject material" of the book.
Conversely, the 1985 book also used "Bender" as a mocking pun for "Ender", but Matt
Groening stated this is not the original inspiration for Bender's name.
The film explores themes of saving the world, role playing, role
playing game, fantasy world, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.